# ZOE ELLEN POINTON

#### **UX DESIGNER**

07935408399

zoepointon123@gmail.com

zoeellenpointon.com

Finishing my masters in Design Informatics, at the University of Edinburgh. 2+ years design experience working within the Tech Industry. Graduated from the University of Winchester with a first class honours in Digital Media Design.

Looking for a new challenge in **user experience design**, starting September 2019.

#### **UX SKILLS**

User Journeys

Prototyping

User Testing

Focus Groups

Wireframes

Card Sorting

Personas

## ANALYTICS SKILLS

Python

D3

#### **DEV SKILLS**

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

### DESIGN TOOLS

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

After Effects

XD

Sketch

Invision

Zeplin

#### AWARDS

UNIVERSITY OF WINCHESTER

Transmedia 2017 Pitch a
Project Winner

## CERTIFICATIONS

GOOGLE

The Online Marketing Fundamentals

# EXPERIENCE

#### TruDigital, Portsmouth - UX/UI Designer

APR 2018 - JUL 2018

Formerly part of CDG. My role in the company was to design and build websites for our SME clients. Working in a start-up setting allowed me to take greater ownership of client projects. I also took a lead role in streamlining the design/development process for the 'affordable' website offering.

#### CDG, Sunningdale - Graduate Designer

MAY 2017 - APR 2018

After graduating I joined CDG as a graduate designer. My role expanded to running client meetings, preparing and conducting focus groups and user testing. As well as working on client projects, I also got the opportunity to work within product teams, creating and refining digital products using agile.

#### CDG, Sunningdale - Digital Design Intern

MAY 2016 - APR 2017

During my last year at university I got the opportunity to work alongside my study. It allowed me to develop my design and problem solving skills and gain new experience creating design mock-ups and prototypes for clients.

# EDUCATION

SEP 2018 - AUG 2019

University of Edinburgh - MA Design Informatics

Predicted Grade: Merit

SEP 2014 - MAY 2017

University of Winchester - BA Digital Media Design

Grade: First

#### REFERENCES

BETTINA NISSEN SALLY HANSON

University of Edinburgh CDG

bettina.nissen@ed.co.uk sally@shml.co.uk

ALLAN CRABTREE

TruDigital

allan@allancrabtree.co.uk